《超女》前情提要
Previously on Supergirl...
做莱克斯·卢瑟做不到的事
Do what Lex Luthor failed to do.
改变这个世界
Change the world.
嘶吼杀了我最好的朋友罗素·罗杰斯
Rip Roar murdered my best friend, Russell Rogers.
超查部抓到了嘶吼  并确认了他的身份
The DEO caught Rip Roar and they were able to ID him.
是罗素
It's Russell.
我把凯特科卖给安德里亚了
I sold CatCo to Andrea.
她和我是故交
She and I go way back,
我们在寄宿学校就认识了
since boarding school.
杰克·斯菲尔和我曾经比较亲密
Jack Spheer and I, we used to be close.
-何时分手的  -在我到纳欣诺市之前
- Until when? - Just before I moved to National City.
你有能力在人们脑中植入想法
You have the ability to incept thoughts into people's minds.
我想研究你的大脑
I want to study your brain,
以开发有相同能力的科技
so I can develop a technology that can do the same thing.
亚丽克斯
Alex!
是什么杀了她
What just killed her?
谢谢你来这里一趟  威廉
Thank you for coming down here, William.
卡拉说能找到嘶吼的人
Kara said if anyone would be able to reach Rip Roar,
只有你
it would be you.
罗素还在  我知道的
Russell's still in there, I know it,
但他一定不是自愿的
but he must be acting against his will.
我认识的那个人绝对不会做出这些可怕的事
The man I knew could've never done all of those terrible things.
没错  18次暗杀行动
Yes, 18 assassinations,
还有一次生态恐怖袭击
plus one ecological terror attack.
一次挫败的恐怖袭击
A thwarted terror attack.
我们都知道嘶吼在替某个人卖命
Well, we know Rip Roar is working for someone.
我要查出是谁  还要他们为什么这样对他
I'm going to find out who and why they did this to him.
我可以肯定他的生物技术还在保护他
I can confirm that his biotech is still shielding him
阻止我们的求真者接近他
from the power of our Truth Seeker.
我们不能把生物技术移除掉吗
Can't we take that biotech off?
这么对他的人
Whoever did this to him
在他的神经系统上
attached incredibly sophisticated technology
装了精密复杂的技术
to his nervous system.
如果移除不当  也许会害死他
If we remove it incorrectly, it may kill him.
有人擅闯超查部
We've been breached.
启动应急程序  保护超查部
Initiate emergency protocol, secure the facility,
布莱尼  我要电力恢复
Brainy, I want that power back up.
艾丽克斯  是影子
Alex, the shadow.
她去哪了
Where'd she go?
我打不中她
I can't get her.
她是冲着嘶吼来的
It's after Rip Roar.
待在这别动
Stay right here.
我不知道你是谁  是什么
I don't know who or what you are.
这是我的犯人  如果你碰他
This is my prisoner and if you touch him,
我就把你打飞
I will light you up.
她走了
She's gone.
超 女
第五季 第六集
安德里亚
Andrea.
你有什么事
What do you want?
我需要你的帮忙
I need your help.
我要打入超查部
I need to break in to the DEO.
超查部是什么
What's the DEO?
别装了
Stop it.
我知道你之前和他们签过政府合同
I know you've had government contracts with them before,
所以我才来找你
that's why I'm here.
好吧
Okay.
假设我们俩都知道超查局是什么
Say we both know what the DEO is.
财富500强企业的总裁为什么需要进入权限
Why does the head of a Fortune 500 company need access?
我知道那场差点毁了纳欣诺市的海浪
I know who was behind the tidal wave
是谁在幕后操控
that almost took out National City.
我知道是因为我替他们做事
I know because I work for them.
但如果我告诉你他们的身份  他们会杀了我
But if I tell who they are, they'll kill me.
还会杀了你
And you too.
超查部抓到了引发海浪的特工
The DEO captured the agent that started the tidal wave.
我效力的人要我在他交代之前杀了他
The people I work for want me to kill him before he can talk.
安德里亚  你来我家
Andrea, you come to my house
叫我帮你去杀人  你疯了吗
and ask for my help to kill someone, are you crazy?
我的确认识超查部局长
You know, I do know the director of the DEO.
我为何不现在就打电话给她举报你呢
What's to stop me from calling her right now and reporting you?
因为我不想杀他
Because I don't want to kill him.
我想救他
I want to save him.
他对来说很重要
He's important to me.
我可以闯进超查部
I can breach the facility.
但是超女在亲自看守他
But Supergirl is guarding him personally
我过不了她那一关
and I can't get past her.
你之前替她做过事
You've worked for her before.
-也许你可以  -不行
- Maybe you can. - No.
抱歉
Sorry.
莉娜
Lena...
我以朋友的身份请求你
I'm asking as a friend.
我们不是朋友
We're not friends.
范霍恩单一麦芽威士忌
我们曾经是
We used to be.
海伦娜山寄宿学校
十五年前
你是那个新来的莉娜  对吧
You're Lena, the new kid, right?
我叫安德里亚
I'm Andrea.
我爸妈也没有来参观
My parents didn't come for visitor day either.
他们为什么没来
Why didn't they come?
我父亲经营一家非常成功的企业
My father runs a very successful business.
所以他很忙
So he's, you know, busy.
而我母亲在巴黎
Mother, on the other hand, is in Paris.
对她来说  我不如她的男爵朋友
I don't interest her nearly as much as her friend,
来得有趣
the baron.
你妈妈呢  我猜猜
What about your mom? Let me guess.
-她在和公爵乱搞吗  -我母亲去世了
- She's off screwing a duke? - My mother's dead.
今晚我们不如去真正派对上玩玩吧
What do you say we go to a real party tonight?
我父亲最爱喝范霍恩威士忌
Van Horne's is my father's favorite drink.
上等威士忌
It's top, top shelf.
他都没看我们的身份证
He didn't even card us.
为什么要看  我们21岁了
Why would he? We're 21.
-我们不是  -莉娜
- No, we're not. - Lena...
得到你想要的事物关键在于自信
The key to getting what you want is confidence.
假装有自信  就没人会质疑我们
Act like you already have it and no one will question us.
我们走
Come on.
最爱看的电影
Favorite movie...
一二三
One, two, three.
《泰坦尼克号》
Titanic.
我在电影院看过八次
I saw it eight times in the theater.
我看过六次
Six times for me.
我哥哥冷酷地嘲笑我
My brother mocked me relentlessly.
让那些喷子滚蛋  我们都该像萝丝一样潇洒
Screw the haters, we should all live like Rose.
你想遇见你的灵魂伴侣
Do you wanna meet your soulmate
却眼睁睁地看着他悲惨地死去吗
only to watch him die tragically?
不  是像《泰坦尼克号》的萝丝那样
No, Rose post -Titanic,
萝丝·道森
Rose Dawson.
她去享受人生
She went out there and grabbed life,
没有浪费一分一秒
didn't waste a single moment.
那是我的梦想  周游列国
That's my dream, go everywhere,
体验一切
experience everything,
同时把我爸爸的公司带上一个新的高度
all while taking my dad's company to the next level.
-这些都是远大的目标  -所以才有意思
- Those are lofty goals. - That's what makes it fun.
我也有类似的梦想
I have a dream like that.
远大的梦想吗
Lofty?
不可能实现的梦想
Impossible.
那你必须要告诉我
Well, now you have to tell me
我母亲以前常给我讲这个
My mother used to always tell me this story
关于阿珂拉塔坠子的故事
about the medallion of the Acrata.
故事说的是一个姑娘的村子
It's about this girl whose village
遭到黑暗势力的破坏
was being ravaged by darkness,
所以她去森林里寻求魔法的帮助
so she went into the wild in search of magic that could help.
然后呢
What happens?
她找到了阿珂拉塔的坠子
She finds the medallion of Acrata
并且得到巨大的天赋
and was bestowed great gifts
所以她才有了力量
so that she alone had the strength
让影子服从她
to bend shadow to her will.
故事是你妈妈编的吗
Did your mom make it up?
她在古老的故事书里看到的
She found it in an old storybook.
她对此很着迷
She was obsessed.
她把这个故事说得像是真的一样
She'd talk about it like it was real.
她到处画那个符号
She'd draw the symbol everywhere.
你在笔记本上乱画的也是这个吗
Is that what you were doodling in your notebook?
她说我等我年长一点
She said when I got older,
等事情变好一点
when things were better,
我们就会去寻找那个符号
that we would go on a quest to find it.
一起去
Together.
太傻了  抱歉
It's stupid. I'm sorry.
不  不傻
No, it's not stupid,
有时这些传说是基于事实
sometimes these legends are based in fact,
如果坠子是真的
and if this medallion is real,
我会帮你找到它的
I'll help you find it.
-你会吗  -正如萝丝所说
- You will? - Like Rose says,
"你跳  我也跳"
"You jump, I jump."
大都会
五年前
我们刚刚与外星种族取得初次接触
We just made fit contact with an alien race
就算不考虑
and even apart from the existential threat
他威胁到我们整个物种的存在
that he poses to our entire species,
我们要怎么去定夺呢
I mean, how can we measure up?
从现在起  这就是...
From now on, this...
卢瑟公司
is Luther Corp.
简直是疯了  你着魔般地要杀死超人
This is insane, your obsession with killing Superman.
我们应该帮人才对
We're supposed to help people.
斯菲瑞科实业公司正在招人
I think Spheerical Industries is hiring.
如果我不帮你杀死超人
If I don't help you murder Superman,
你要开除我
you're firing me?
我不会让你杀了他
I am not gonna let you kill him.
阿根廷  罗哈斯庄园
爸爸  你准备好了吗
Papa, you almost ready?
车子在等了
The car's waiting.
新型T像素8将会引起
The new T-Pixel 8 will excite...
爸爸  你快穿衣服
Papa, you have to get dressed,
一小时后就要去黑曜石的新手机发布会了
we have Obsidian Worldwide's new phone launch in an hour.
-媒体在等  -并没有
- The press is waiting. - No, they're not.
罗德工业刚发布了新型T像素8
Lord Industry just announced a new T-Pixel 8.
芯片比我们快四倍
The chip is four times faster than ours.
四倍  不可能
Four times? That's impossible.
我们要亏几十亿
We are going to lose billions.
必须在圣诞前卖出公司的
We have to let go of 70% of the company
七成股份
by Christmas.
我的公司要是废了
If my company is worthless,
我就废了
my life is worthless.
你的人寿保险单过期了吗
Why is your life insurance policy out?
你说好不再这样的  爸爸
You promised you wouldn't do this again, Papa.
你是我人生里最美好的一部分
You are the best thing in my life.
我不会毁了你
I refuse to ruin you.
走吧  去做更光彩的事  我的宝贝
Go and do something better, mi cielito.
你被解雇了
Consider yourself fired.
莉娜
Lena.
我现在真的很需要你的意见
You're just the voice I needed to hear right now.
我们不知道情况会有多糟糕
We won't know how bad things really are for us
要等到下周董事会决定
until next week when the board decides
是提前发布手机还是直接放弃
to either push the launch of the phone or kill it completely.
在那之前  爸爸一直待在实验室
Papa's locked himself away in his lab till then.
我以前也见他这样  但从没这么严重
I've seen him bad before but never like this.
他昨天的样子
The way he looked yesterday,
吓到我了
it scared me.
你呢  卢瑟公司那边怎么样
Oh, how about you? How are things going in Luther Corp?
遇到家族生意危机的不止你一个人
You're not the only one with family business problems.
莱克斯彻底疯了
Lex is completely unhinged.
他对超人的执念已经失控了
His obsession with Superman is out of control.
他不惜一切要杀了超人
He'll stop at nothing to kill him
我非常担心
and I am very afraid that
很多人会因此受伤
a lot of people are going to get hurt...
甚至牺牲
or killed in the process.
-你能阻止他吗  -他把我开了
- Can't you stop him? - He pushed me out.
莱克斯的最新计划
I mean, Lex's latest plan
就是把氪石散布到大气中
is to seed the atmosphere with Kryptonite.
氪石是什么
What is Kryptonite?
据莱克斯说  那是超人最大的弱点
According to Lex, it's Superman's greatest weakness.
-他能做到吗  -还不能
- Can he do it? - No, not yet.
首先  他要想办法让氪石升华成气体
First, he has to figure out how to sublimate it into vapor,
他相信一个荒谬理论  某种古老的外星元素
but he has this mad theory that this ancient alien element
可以帮到他
is going to help him do that.
这种元素在几百万年前砸到地球上
I mean, this element crash-landed on Earth millions of years ago.
要从莱克斯手底下
All I need to do to...
拯救全人类  我只需要
save humanity from Lex's madness is...
在他之前找到这种元素
find the element first.
你已经找到了  对吧
You already found it, didn't you?
多亏了你
Thanks to you.
你还记得你那篇人类学的论文吗
Okay, so do you remember your anthropology dissertation
讲的是在火山阴影下的阿兹特克村庄
about the Aztec village that lived in the shadow of the volcano
虽然经历过多次火山爆发
but never got covered in lava
却从未被岩浆覆盖
no matter how much the volcano erupted?
你觉得外星元素就在那里吗
And you think that's where the alien element is?
我对那片地区做了深度卫星扫描
I did an intensive satellite scan of the area
然后发现了
and I found...
这个
this.
是你以前画的符号
It's that symbol you used to draw.
阿珂拉塔的坠子
The medallion of Acrata.
我母亲的故事把我引向
What are the odds that my mother's story
能够阻止我哥的东西
would lead me to the one thing
这种可能性有多大
that has the properties I need to stop my brother?
-简直是奇迹  -是命运
- It's crazy. - It's fate.
好吧  这里的信号最强烈
All right, so that's where the signature is strongest,
我们要去这里
so we need to get to it.
我们
We?
不不不  我现在不能走  我父亲需要我
No, no, no, I can't leave right now, my father needs me.
我知道  但最多只要三天
I know, but it's three days, tops,
我保证  而且你自己也说
I promise, and you yourself said that the board
董事会得下周才能做决定
wasn't going to be making a decision for another week.
拜托
Please.
我哥哥在邪恶的道路上越走越远
My brother is in a downward spiral
只有我能救他了
and I am the only one who can save him from himself.
但我一个人做不到
But I can't do it alone.
好吗  你学过这种文化
All right? You studied this culture,
你熟悉这片地区和语言
you know the area and the language.
而且这不是你一直想要的吗
Besides, isn't it what you always wanted?
实地探索  感受自然
To go out there and grab life?
走吧
Come on.
萝丝·道森会怎么做
What would Rose Dawson do?
"你跳我就跳  对吧"
"You jump, I jump, right?"
哥斯达黎加丛林
没路了
或许可以绕过去或穿过去
Maybe there's a way around it or through it.
等等
Wait.
"她周围的一切变成岩石"
"And when the world around her turned to stone,"
"在这无望的时刻  女孩低头看向地核"
"impenetrable by hope, the girl looked down to the core"
"发现了蜿蜒的路"
"and was shown the winding way."
蛇  代表箭
The snake, it's an arrow,
我们往这边走
we go this way.
厉害
That's impressive.
传说中的X肯定就在这附近
The proverbial "X" Must be around here someplace.
看
Look.
阿兹特克的蛇头花
Aztec serpent-headed flowers.
书里的女孩跟蛇头打斗过吗
Didn't the girl from the book fight the head of a snake?
不
No!
安德里亚
Andrea.
天啊  你没事吧
Oh, my God, are you okay?
还活着
Yeah, still in one piece.
-应该  -我们做个绳梯给你爬
- I think. - We'll make a rope ladder and get you out.
你待着别动
Stay right there.
莉娜  等等
Lena, wait.
安德里亚·罗哈斯
Andrea Rojas.
-你是谁  -我是信使
- Who are you? - I am a messenger.
就这么简单
Nothing more, nothing less.
蛇头花会引起幻觉
Serpent-headed flowers, they have psychedelic properties
我眼前的是幻觉  一定是
and I'm hallucinating, that's what this is.
这是真实的  我可以向你保证
Oh, this is very real, I assure you.
送我来的人  也是真实的
As they are who sent me,
利维坦
Leviathan.
他们想要什么
What do they want?
你父亲  贝尔纳多·罗哈斯
Your father, Bernardo Rojas,
状况不好  对吧
he's not well, is he?
你怎么
How do you...
他是个好人
He's a brilliant man.
他会好起来的
Things will turn around for him.
他没有你想的那么坚强了
He's not as strong as you believe him to be,
我的宝贝
mi cielito.
他很快就要失去一切了
He's on the brink of ending everything,
所以你才对他那么上心
that is why you devote yourself to him.
你想要我怎么样
What do you want from me?
你的幸福和臣服  一物换一物
Your happiness and your service, one for the other.
-什么意思  -你只需要知道
- What does that mean? - What matters now
如果你同意  你父亲就能活得好好的
is if you agree, your father will live and live well.
你只要拿上这个
All you have to do is take this.
不
No.
不  不  不行
No, no, no, I can't.
我朋友莉娜需要这个
My friend Lena, she needs this.
这是她最想要的
This is all she's ever wanted.
你还想救你爸爸吗
You want to save your father or not?
拿上坠子
Take the medallion.
接受你的命运
Accept your fate.
要一直戴在身上
Keep it on you always.
不要提起  否则你会失去一切所爱
Never speak of it or all that you love will be lost.
记住  有一天
And remember, there will come a day
我们会召唤你
when we will call upon you.
做好准备
Be prepared.
安德里亚
Andrea.
安德里亚  我这就下来
Andrea, I'll be right there.
你没事吧  我很担心
Are you okay? I was so worried.
没事  我只是想赶紧离开
Yeah, I just wanna get out of here.
好
Okay.
就是这个  安德里亚  我们找到了
This is it, Andrea, we found it.
这就是那个坠子
It's the medallion.
雕刻图案也符合故事里的描述
These etchings, they match the description in the story.
我的计算没错
My calculations were right.
我妈妈的话没错
My mother was right.
但它在哪里  应该在这里
But where is it? It looks like it should be here.
可能被别人抢先了
Maybe someone got to it first.
不可能  就在这里  肯定在这里
No, it has to be here, it's supposed to be here,
肯定有痕迹的  卫星
there should be some kind of trace, the satellites--
可能出错
Are fallible.
你检测到的可能是别的东西
You could have been picking up anything.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  我们继续找
Okay, we'll keep looking,
查出是谁  什么时候来过这里
we'll figure out who was here and when--
莉娜  听着  找到这里已经很不容易了
Lena, look, finding this place was hard enough.
想看到来过这里或者会来这里的人
Seeing who came before or after,
简直不可能
it's impossible.
就差一点
I was so close.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
爸爸
Papa?
还没有
No, no, I haven't.
洛德工业是真打算把市场"炸"了
Lord Industries is blowing up the market literally.
洛德工业手机灾难
他们最新的智能手机芯片有问题
Their latest smartphone contains a faulty chip
会导致设备爆炸
causing devices to explode.
但他们的失误对黑曜石全球是好事
But their loss is Obsidian Worldwide's gain.
黑曜石全球公司股票达到历史最高
他们的股票今天飙到了历史新高
Their stock hit an all-time high today.
爸爸
Papa.
很了不起
That's incredible.
-镜头交给你  瑞克  -谢谢
- Now back to you, Rick. - Thank you for that...
这下我们的形势只会越来越好
I think things are only going to get better for us.
四年前  大都会
卢瑟女士
Ms. Luthor.
你哥哥为什么把太阳变红
Why did your brother turn the sun red?
超人
Superman.
卢瑟女士不会在律师不在场的情况下
Ms. Luthor won't be answering any questions
回答任何问题
without a lawyer present.
杰克
Jack.
我真是太傻了
I was such an idiot.
我还以为自己能拯救他  怎么救
I thought I could save him with what?
-靠一厢情愿吗  -你是相信了他内心的善良
- Magical thinking? - You believed in the good in him.
这很有意义
That means something.
-有吗  -我们走吧
- Does it? - Let's get out of here,
先离开这里
out of town for a while.
我在伦敦有个会  你跟我一起去吧
I have that conference in London, come with me.
伦敦
你说得对
You were right.
我需要这样
I needed this.
再次看到你的笑容真好
It's nice to see you smiling again.
-你去展现魅力吧  我去拿酒  -好
- Go be charming. I'll get drinks. - Right. Okay.
安德里亚
Andrea.
莉娜
Lena.
我没想到你会来
I had no idea you'd be here,
我不知道你来了伦敦
I didn't know that you were in London.
等等  那是什么
Wait, what's that?
我就知道
I knew it.
坠子明明在  是你拿走的
The medallion was there, and you're the one that took it
你明知道它对我有多重要
even though you knew how much it meant to me.
为什么
Why?
听我说  有些事情
Look, there are things I couldn't...
我不能告诉你
That I can't tell you.
你看着我的眼睛  却骗了我
You looked me in the eye and you lied to me.
你是我在这世上最信任的人
I trusted you more than anyone in the world
可你却让我像个傻子
and you made a fool out of me.
我以为卢瑟家的人可能会这样背叛我
You know, I expect this kind of betrayal
真没想到会是你
from the Luthors, but not you.
-莉娜  别这样  -你说什么都没用
- Lena, please. - There's nothing you can say.
我们结束了
We're done.
大都会 两个月后
伦敦回来之后  你就变了个人
Ever since London, you've been a completely different person,
很少跟我说话
you've barely talked to me
现在居然要离开大都会
and now you're leaving Metropolis?
我有责任为我哥哥
It's my responsibility to make up for the stain
在这世上造的孽做些补偿
my brother left on the world.
做点好事
To do something good.
我们本来就计划做好事啊
We were going to do something good.
一起做  那我们的公司怎么办
Together. What about our company?
你看到了吗  所以我才需要待在纳欣诺市
You see this? This is why I need to be in National City.
超女阻止了大量袭击
那里有人做好事  在帮助别人
There are people doing good there, who are trying to help.
如果我留在大都会  我将永远是
If I stay in Metropolis, I will always be the sister
一个自私自利的疯子的妹妹
of the egomaniacal lunatic,
可如果我去纳欣诺市
but I go to National City,
我就可以成为与氪星人共享家园的卢瑟家人
I can be the Luthor that shares her home with a Kryptonian.
成为帮助她维护世界稳定
That helps her put the world back together
而不是破坏世界和平的人
instead of tearing it apart.
你知道我不能离开  莉娜
You know I can't leave, Lena.
我不是让你离开
I'm not asking you to.
所以
So...
你要选择去挽回卢瑟家族的名声
So you're choosing to redeem the Luthor name?
放弃我
Over me.
放弃我们
Over us.
莉娜  别这样  跟我聊聊
Lena, please, look, talk to me.
你可以信任我
You can trust me.
我现在谁都不能信任了
I can't trust anyone anymore.
我回工作室了
Going back to the studio.
莱克斯·卢瑟的审讯不断震惊全国人民
And the trial of Lex Luthor continues to shock the nation,
莱克斯·卢瑟接受庭审
让所有人都无比清晰地看到
painting a vivid picture of just how far
曾经伟大的卢瑟家族如何声名扫地
the once great name of Luthor has fallen.
也许是我错了  但大家称之为"喝的"
I might be mistaken, but I'm pretty sure they call that a drink
应该就是说它是用来喝的吧
'cause that's what you're supposed to do with it.
可能我没那个心情
I guess I'm not in the mood.
恰恰相反  我买醉的时候就是你这个表情
I usually do all my drinking when I feel the way you look.
就像你刚失去了世上最后一个朋友
Like you've just lost your last friend in the world.
你一定很忙  祝你喝得愉快
Well, I'm sure you're very busy, enjoy your drink.
其实
Actually...
我现在一点都不忙
I've got nothing but free time right now.
别人放我鸽子了
I've been stood up.
-这么惨  -没事
- Ouch. - That's all right.
我本来也打算拒绝对方
I was going to reject them anyway.
那不是挺好的
Then it all worked out.
也许吧
I guess it did.
你呢
What about you?
是什么让你坐在这里不喝酒
What drove you to a day of heavy non-drinking?
我本来有一场重要会议  结果完全忘了
I had a big meeting and I completely forgot about it.
这很不像我
It's so unlike me,
我一般都很追求完美  不过
I'm usually type A, but...
被朋友的事干扰了
But the friend thing got in the way.
你怎么会知道
Okay, how do you know that?
我不知道  我只是也有个好朋友而已
I didn't, I just have a best friend too, that's all.
对了  我叫安德里亚
I'm Andrea, by the way.
我知道
Oh, I know.
我是罗素·罗杰斯
I'm Russell Rogers.
我把你的会议给吹了
You're the meeting I blew off?
你从什么时候发现的
How long did you know?
你提到有重要会议之后
Only since you mentioned a business meeting.
我发誓
I swear.
等等  你是打算拒绝黑曜石的邀请吗
Wait, you said that you were gonna turn down Obsidian's offer?
这下尴尬了
Well, now, this is awkward.
抱歉我不能接受那个职位
I'm afraid I can't accept the position.
我要创建自己的公司
I'm starting my own company
专注做电子仿生学
focusing solely on cyber-bionics.
当然这纯属临时起意
Which is fortuitous on many levels.
但主要是我想请你吃晚餐
But mostly because I'd like to ask you to dinner.
而如果你是我老板的话
Which could've gotten very dicey
情况就会有点棘手
if you were my employer.
你怎么说
So what do you say?
纳欣诺市 三年前
纳欣诺市爆炸新闻
Breaking news from National City.
莉娜·卢瑟  纳欣诺市的新兴知名人士
Lena Luthor, National City's newest predominant resident,
莉娜·卢瑟遭袭
今天遭到歹徒暗杀
was rescued from an assassination attempt today
被氪星超人和超女救下
by the Kryptonian duo of Superman and Supergirl.
地下搏击俱乐部虐待外星人
这不是纳欣诺市的新兴记者吗
Well, if it isn't National City's newest hotshot reporter.
-我正在看你的文章  -我就是来说这个的
- I was just reading your article. - That's actually why I'm here,
我想谢谢你帮我找到那家搏击俱乐部
I have to say thank you for helping me find that fight club.
你刚来这里一个月  就已经多次
You've been in the city a month and you've already saved my job
拯救了我的工作
an embarrassing amount of times.
我相信等时机来临  你会报答我的
Well, I am sure you will return the favor when the time comes.
说到这个
On that note,
我还想把这个给你
I also wanted to give you this.
有人窃取了L公司的邮件记录
Someone hacked into the emails at L-Corp
匿名发给了凯特科
and sent them to CatCo anonymously.
我拦截了这段记录
I was able to snag the data
里面包含一些有些尴尬的内容
and there are some potentially embarrassing things in there,
但是大部分内容  不值得报道
but for the most part, it's not newsworthy.
我只是记得你说过
I just remember you saying
你想在家族之外  为自己立名
you want to make a name for yourself outside of your family
我不希望哪个混蛋毁了你的梦想
and I would hate for some jerk to ruin that.
我知道出现了漏洞  但我以为解决了
I knew there'd been a breach but I thought we caught everything.
谢谢你  卡拉
Thank you, Kara.
你知道你可以怎么谢我吗
You know how you could thank me?
我和我姐姐会举办游戏之夜  每次都赢
We have this game night thing and my sister and I dominate
我们很想找一个足以匹敌的对手
and we are in desperate need of a worthy adversary.
抱歉  卡拉  我之前说
I'm sorry, Kara, when I said I wanted us
希望我们有一段积极的关系
to have a positive relationship,
是因为我觉得我们可以互相帮助
it was because I thought we could help each other.
但我要说清楚  我是指商务合作
But let me be clear, I meant a business relationship.
我希望你把这些邮件给我
I would hate for you to give me these emails
不是因为你错觉我们可以当朋友
out of some misplaced sense of friendship.
我不是来这里交朋友的
I didn't come here to make friends,
所以你请便
so by all means,
把邮件公开吧
publish the emails.
我不会那样做的  莉娜
I would never do that, Lena.
但如果你改变主意  欢迎你来
But if you change your mind, the invite always stands.
每周五晚
Every Friday night.
一家素食餐厅怎么能不注明呢
How can a vegan restaurant not identify itself?
-太残忍了  -我知道
- It's cruel. - I know.
我们恋爱六个月纪念日就这么毁了
Our six-month anniversary ruined.
我提议重新庆祝一次
You know, I vote for a do-over.
烧烤怎么样
Barbecue?
别说得这么性感
Stop talking so sexy.
-今晚见  -好的
- See you tonight? - Yes.
他很帅气
He's very handsome.
对不起我身上没有现金
Sorry, I don't have any cash on me.
我不要你的钱  我要你兑现承诺
I don't need your money, just what you promised.
你帮我干活
Your service.
你知道利维坦总有一天会来找你的
You knew there would be a time when Leviathan would call on you.
你想要什么
What do you want from me?
去这个地址
Go to this location,
找到这张卡上的男人
find the man on this card
然后杀了他
and kill him.
-我不是杀手  -你是不是  我说了算
- I'm not a killer. - You are what we say you are.
你以前虽然不成功  但我们却助你登天
You weren't successful and then we said you were.
你父亲曾有自杀倾向  但现在却没有了
Your father was suicidal and now he's not.
你真的觉得这一切都没有代价吗
Did you really think all of this didn't come with a price?
我不会这么做的
I won't do it.
你拒绝我们  但是
You refuse us, but...
明天你父亲就会被控内幕交易
a day from now your father will be accused of insider trading,
股票将会暴跌  公司将遭受重创
stocks will tumble, the company will be decimated.
一天晚上  在等待审判时
One night, while awaiting trial,
你父亲将会穿上条纹睡衣
your father will put on his striped pajamas,
搭乘电梯到达屋顶
he will take the elevator to the roof
当他踏上窗台时
and when he steps up on the ledge,
他的遗言将会是
his last words will be,
"我辜负了你们  我的市民"
"I failed you, mi cielito."
认真听我说
Listen to me very carefully.
拿好坠子  摁三次
Take the medallion, tap it three times,
接下来你会知道怎么做的
you'll know what to do.
哈珀州长
Governor Harper?
Governor Harper!
上个月  凯特·格兰特加入了默斯坦行政部门
Last month, Cat Grant joined the Merstan Administration,
自从上任  她就影响了很多人
and since her appointment she's made a great impact.
今日科技
Today and Technology is...
莉娜
Lena.
卡拉
Kara.
你好  很高兴见到你
Hi, it's really good to see you.
你在等人吗
Are you waiting for someone?
今天没有  我要和电子表格亲密约会
Not today, I have a hot date with some spreadsheets.
我要在这里和我姐姐见面  她很爱这里
I'm actually meeting my sister here, she loves it.
她常点菜单上的每一份开胃菜
She makes us order every appetizer on the menu.
其实  是我常点所有开胃菜
Actually, I'm lying, I'm the one that orders all the appetizers.
-听上去很好玩  -是的
- That sounds like fun. - Yeah.
我知道你说
Look, I heard you when you said
你不想和任何人有关联
you didn't wanna connect with anyone
但是我曾经也是初来乍到
but I've been the new girl in town
所以我也提高自己的警惕
and I put my guards up too.
但是我生活得很惨
But I was miserable.
如果我没有对别人打开心扉  对我的姐姐
And if I hadn't let someone in, my sister,
说真的
actually...
我觉得我可能会喘不过气
I think I would've drowned in it.
那么
And...
我姐姐似乎要去工作
I guess my sister has to work.
我  你也要工作
I... You do, too,
对不起  我先走了
I'm sorry, I'll leave you alone.
卡拉
Kara.
别开玩笑了  你一个人吃不了所有开胃菜
Don't be ridiculous, you can't eat all those apps on your own.
不如和我一起吃
Why don't you join me.
真的吗
Really?
好的  但是我提醒你
Okay, but I'm warning you,
人们几年来一直低估了
people have been underestimating
我有多少能吃
how much I can eat for years.
尽管来吧
Oh, game on.
否认气候变化者被暗影刺客谋杀
-你没事吧  -罗素
- You all right? - Russ.
伦敦
你回来得真早
Hey, you're home early.
你怎么了
What's going on?
你这几周一直心事重重的
Something's been off with you for weeks.
我担心你被卷进了什么坏事
I'm worried you're into something bad.
危险的事
Something dangerous.
那只是
It's just, um...
一件家庭私事
A private family thing.
我很累了
Look, I'm exhausted,
我去洗个澡
I'm gonna go take a shower.
你们在干什么  不  停下
What are you doing? No, stop!
你知道利维坦要求绝对的谨慎
You know Leviathan required complete discretion.
你粗心大意  让他过于接近真相
You were careless, he got too close.
我们的秘密比任何生命都重要
Our secrets are more important than any life.
不不不  他是个好人
No, no, no, he's a good person.
这不是他的错  拜托
This isn't his fault, please.
杀了他  布置成入室抢劫
Finish it, make it look like a home invasion.
不  等等
No, wait!
他可以帮你们
He can help you.
他是罗素·罗杰斯
This is Russell Rogers,
他研究医学前沿科技
he's working on medical advancements.
他研发出的原型可以
He has a prototype that can bring soldiers back
挽救濒死士兵等等
from the brink of death and then some.
他对你们来说会很有用
He can be very useful to you.
没事的
It's okay.
你的朋友们
Your friends...
十二个月前
从一开始就一直在对你撒谎
have been lying to you from the start.
所有人
Every last one.
十个月前
过去五年
...the last five years.
我们有莱克斯·卢瑟的最新消息
And we have an update on the Lex Luthor story.
莱克斯·卢瑟和他操纵卡兹尼亚人的计划
Lex Luthor and his master plan to manipulate the Kaznians.
钢铁女侠再一次拯救了世界
The Girl of Steel saves the day again.
-超女拯救了  -黑曜石全球这周宣布
- Supergirl saved-- - Obsidian Worldwide announced
他们将会设立由贝尔纳多·罗哈斯总裁的女儿
this week that they will be opening a new branch to be spearheaded
安德里亚管理的新分部
by CEO Bernardo Rojas' daughter Andrea Rojas.
黑曜石公司进入北美市场
Obsidian's entrance into the North American market
标志着公司的一个转折点
marks a turning point for the company
此公司之前从未涉足美国市场
which has thus far avoided the American market.
贝尔纳多·罗哈斯总裁曾是一位英勇的开拓者
CEO Bernando Rojas, once a gallant trailblazer...
我从未需要过它们
I never needed them.
任何东西
Any of them.
但这不意味着它们就毫无用处
But that doesn't mean they can't be useful.
我很高兴你打电话给我  莉娜
I was glad to get a call from you, Lena.
八周前
我很想你
I've missed you.
好久不见
It's been a long time.
我以为再也听不到你的消息了
I thought I'd never hear from you again.
我在想
Well, I was thinking...
你和我有太多地方可以互相帮助
that you and I have too much to offer each other
不能让过去影响我们现在的合作关系
to let ancient history get in the way of a potential partnership.
好的
Okay.
我洗耳恭听
I'm listening.
你肯定听说了莱克斯最近的恶行
Well, I'm sure you've heard of Lex's latest misdeeds.
他留给我一大堆烂摊子要收拾
He's left me with quite a mess to clean up.
财政上而言
Financially.
所以我要出售凯特科
So I'm selling CatCo.
-真遗憾  -我很高兴你这么想
- That's a shame. - I'm glad you think so.
因为我觉得我找到了最合适的人来接手
Because I believe I've found the perfect person to take it over.
你
You.
我已经在管理一家科技公司了
I already run a tech company.
科技能给你钱  但是媒体能给你市场控制权
Tech gets you money, but media gets you control of the markets.
凯特科会是黑曜石之北公司最好的
And CatCo would be the perfect advertising platform
宣传平台
for Obsidian.
这是个有趣的想法
That's an interesting thought,
说实话我从没这么考虑过
I've honestly never considered it.
你应该好好想想
You should.
我知道你一直在为
And I know you'v been looking for a place
黑曜石之北的新总部选址
for Obsidian North's new headquarters.
我觉得纳欣诺市是最合适的地方
I think National City could be a good fit.
再回到同一个城市真的很好
It would be nice to be in the same city again.
就像以前一样
Just like old times.
我们何不谈谈交易细节
Why don't we discuss the details?
现今
我每次看见你
Every time I look at you,
都想起自己做过的所有糟糕的事情
I'm reminded of all the horrible things I've done.
亲爱的  我每次看见你
Honey, every time I look at you,
想起的都是疼痛
all I remember is pain.
莉娜  很久以来我一直想告诉你真相  但是
Lena, for so long I wanted to tell you the truth, but...
我很害怕
I was scared.
那个坠子是唯一能够
That medallion was the only thing
阻止我哥哥的东西
that could've stopped my brother
-而且你是知道的  -我做的所有事
- and you knew that. - Everything I did,
所有决定都是为了救我父亲的性命
every decision was to save my father's life.
我哥哥是个杀人狂
My brother was a homicidal maniac.
许多无辜的人都因为你和他而死了
A lot of innocent people are dead because of him, because of you.
我很清楚我双手沾了多少鲜血
I am well aware of how much blood there is on my hands.
我很对不起
And I'm so sorry.
只是因为你说了对不起
Because you say you're sorry,
并不意味着一切都会好起来
it doesn't make everything better.
我现在要怎么相信你
Okay? How am I supposed to believe you now?
因为你一直都是对的
Because you were right all along.
它有魔力
It was magical.
莉娜
Lena.
"她拥有操控影子的能力"
"And she had the strength to bend shadow to her will."
这不是比喻战胜黑暗  而是字面意思
It wasn't a metaphor about overcoming darkness, it was literal.
这还有穿过阴影的能力
It came with the ability to move through shadows.
你一直都有这个能力吗
And you've had this ability the whole time?
这不是个天赋  这是个诅咒
It's not a gift, it's a curse.
我从没想过背叛你
I never wanted to betray you.
但我的父亲  他要死了
But my father, he was gonna die...
我别无选择
so I did what I had to do.
但这让我失去了挚爱之人和最好的朋友
But it cost me the love of my life and my best friend.
拿走你的这个是我这辈子最大的错
Taking this from you was the biggest mistake of my life.
我知道我做过很多可怕的事情
I know I've done terrible things.
但这是我做好事的机会
But this is my chance to do something good.
求你了  你必须要相信我
Please, you have to believe me.
我相信你
I believe you.
我受够了人们的相互伤害
I'm tired of people hurting each other.
造成损伤
Doing harm.
所以你会帮助我吗
So you'll help me?
"你跳  我就跳  不是吗"
"You jump, I jump, right?"
-布莱尼有说什么吗  -还没有
- Did Brainy say anything? - Not yet.
但是保管库里有一个卡德摩斯的老技术
But there is an old piece of Cadmus tech in the vaults
或许可以帮我们移除他的生物技术
that could help us remove his biotech
逼他回答
and force answer out of him.
所以我现在去拿
So I'll go get it.
威廉跟我说过你的事
William told me about you,
他跟我说过罗素  说他是个多么优秀的朋友
well, he told me about Russell, how good a friend he was,
失去他是多么的痛心
how devastating it was to lose him.
威廉牺牲了一切
You know, William sacrificed everything,
他一心想要知道罗素发生了什么事
dedicated himself to finding out what happened to Russell.
所以我猜你一定很特别
So I guess you must've been pretty special.
威廉认识的那个人已经消失了
The person William knew is gone.
我不这么认为
I don't agree.
我认为你在为别人干事
I think you're working for someone
他们强迫你做这些事情
and they're forcing you to do these things.
我知道你觉得自己已经走得太远
I know you feel you've gone too far
已经不能再当罗素了  但你错了
to ever be Russell again but you're wrong.
弥补过错永远不晚
It is never too late to try to make things right.
或者至少让事态好转
Or at least better.
这是谁干的
Who did this to you?
我可以保护你
I can keep you safe.
他们叫利维坦
They're called Leviathan.
很好
Good.
接下来这样
Now here's how this will go.
我来控制超女
I'll handle Supergirl.
我要走了
I have to go, um...
谢谢你
Thank you.
莉娜  莉娜
Lena. Lena?
-莉娜  莉娜  -卡拉
- Lena. Lena. - Kara.
谢天谢地你来了
Oh, thank God you're here.
太可怕了  前一分钟还在  转眼就消失了
It was horrible, it was here one minute and gone the next,
她就像个影子
she's like a shadow.
信号干扰启动
我来干扰所有传入信号
I'll jam all incoming signals.
我最近开发了一个可以往附近区域
I've recently developed a device that can incept a single thought
植入一个想法的装置  "别造成伤害"
into the surrounding area, "Do no harm."
把装置放在超查部
Plant it at the DEO.
它将使所有妨碍你的特工失去能力
It will disable all agents that get in your way.
我会在这里控制它
I'll control it from here
然后超查部就是你的了
and then the DEO is yours.
荣恩  有事吗
J'onn, is everything okay?
我感觉到有人精神攻击了超查部
I felt a psychic attack at the DEO.
感觉像是我的哥哥
It felt like my brother.
那不可能
That's impossible.
肯定是其他东西
There must be something else.
我有种不好的预感
I just have a bad feeling.
我们还有精神力抑制器耳塞
Well, we still have the psychic inhibitor buds.
-我会小心的  -好的  一会儿见
- I'll be careful. - Okay, see you soon.
超女  我们这里出了点状况
Supergirl, I think we have a bit of a situation here.
超女  收到了吗
Supergirl, do you copy?
丹弗斯局长
Director Danvers.
多克斯特工  有人植入了超查部
Agent Dox, someone incepted the DEO,
只有我们两个没有受到影响
we're the only two unaffected.
这是一个错误的假设
That is an erroneous assumption.
我们不能造成伤害
We must do no harm.
抱歉了  布莱尼
Sorry, Brainy.
我就知道我感觉到了什么
I knew I felt something.
超女在哪里
Where is Supergirl?
该死的
Oh, hell no.
-不要让影子靠近嘶吼  -好
- Make sure the shadow doesn't get to Rip Roar. - Right.
超女
Supergirl!
艾丽克斯有麻烦了  待在这里
Alex is in trouble, stay here.
别走  别走
No, no.
如果你认为你能伤害我的朋友们
If you think you can hurt my friends,
来赶我走  那你的麻烦就更大了
to get me out of the way, you got another thing coming.
请不要战斗  我想帮助你
Please don't fight. I want to help you.
不
No!
莉娜  我真不知道该怎么报答你
Lena, I honestly don't know how I can ever repay you.
你可以先把坠子还给我
You can start by giving me the medallion.
我不行
I can't.
你要植入我  让我把坠子给你
You'd incept me to give you this.
比这更糟糕
Much worse.
罗素  拿起手术刀
Russell, pick up the scalpel.
把它放在你的颈动脉
Now hold it to your carotid artery.
抵住  慢慢地
And press. Slowly.
求你了  莉娜  不要这样
Please, Lena, don't do this.
那把坠子给我
Then give me the medallion.
你由始至终都想要这个
This is what you wanted this whole time.
我帮你救了罗素  这是我应得的
I helped you save Russell, now I want what I deserve.
我走投无路了  我父亲很虚弱  要死了
I was desperate, my father was weak, he was going to die.
我做的所有事都是因为爱
Everything I did, I did for love.
那才是最伤人的地方
That's what hurt the most.
我比世界上任何人都更在乎你
I cared about you more than anyone else in the world
我永远不会背叛你
and I never would've betrayed you.
我跟你说过这是个诅咒
I told you this thing is a curse.
我们的友谊就是诅咒
Our friendship was the curse.
罗素  放下手术刀
Russell, put the scalpel down.
走吧  你俩都走
Now go, both of you.
马拉法克一定是和杀手合作了
Malefic must've been working with the assassin.
不然他怎么能植入所有人
How else could he have incepted everyone?
相信我  我想知道这是谁干的
Believe me, I want to know who is responsible,
但不是马拉法克
but Malefic did not do this.
所以我们又回到了起点
So we're back to square one.
不尽然  我从嘶吼那里得到了一些东西
We're not, I got something from Rip Roar.
一个名字
A name.
利维坦
Leviathan.
我们马上去收集信息
We'll start gathering intel immediately.
好的  但我要先去说些坏消息
Okay, but I have to break some bad news first.
罗素逃了
Russell got away.
昨天袭击的那个人又来了
The same operative that attacked yesterday came again,
他们同流合污  现在他消失了
they worked as a team and now he's gone.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我一直都看错他了
I was wrong about him all along.
不  我不那么认为
No, I don't think you were.
超女告诉我们他一直是被迫行事
Supergirl told us he's been working against his will.
我觉得他不是故意背叛你
I don't think he ever meant to betray you.
对不起  如果不是因为我
I'm sorry, if it weren't for me,
他们那不会找上你
they never would've come for you.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
即使没有这件事  你也让生活变得有价值
Even before that, you made it worth living.
不  罗素  不不  罗素
No. Russ, no, no, Russ.
不要啊
No, no, no!
救命啊
Somebody help, please.
罗素  救命啊
Russ! Please, somebody help!
你逃不出我们的手掌心
You can't escape us,
也逃不出我们赋予你的力量
nor the powers we bestowed upon you.
我都没有坠子了
I don't even have the medallion anymore.
你想要什么
What do you want?
能力并非来自坠子
The powers never came from the medallion.
是坠子激活了能力
It activated them.
但能力是来自你内心的黑暗
But they came from the darkness within you.
这是你永远无法逃避的
And that is something you can never escape.
不
No...
不要啊
No.
被跑那么快  莉娜  我要抓到你了
Not so fast, Lena, I'm gonna get you.
我抓到你了
I got you.
不要呀  不要呀
Oh, no, no.
我找到了  母亲
I found it, Mother.
结束模拟
End simulation.
卢瑟女士  初步测试证实这个坠子的特性
Ms. Luthor, preliminary tests confirm any properties
都已经消失了
the medallion may have had are gone.
没关系  你能翻译这些标记吗
Doesn't matter, can you translate these markings?
利维坦
现在读取伊芙·泰斯马克的记忆
Now access the memories of Eve Tessmacher
告诉我她知道关于利维坦的一切
and tell me everything she knows about Leviathan.